<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Proposals concerning the printing of a chronological history of England.</title>
            <author>Sammes, Aylett, 1636?-1679?</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1677</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09947</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC"> 80923576</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S536</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183220</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">80923576</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 80923576</idno>
            <idno type="VID">191990</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09947)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 191990)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; 1641-1700 ; 2897:16)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Proposals concerning the printing of a chronological history of England.</title>
                  <author>Sammes, Aylett, 1636?-1679?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1677.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Sammes, Aylett, 1636?-1679? --  Britannia antiqua illustrata, or, The antiquities of ancient Britain.</term>
               <term>Booksellers and bookselling --  England --  Colportage, subscription trade, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Publishers and publishing --  England --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:191990:1"/>
            <head>PROPOSALS Concerning the Printing of a <hi>CHRONOLOGICAL HISTORY</hi> OF ENGLAND.</head>
            <p>THE Firſt Volume is <hi>Britannia Antiqua Illuſtrata,</hi> or the Antiquities of Ancient <hi>Britain,</hi> Derived from the <hi>Phoenicians;</hi> wherein the Original Trade of this Iſland is diſcovered, the names of Places, Offices, Dignities, as likewiſe the Idolatry, Language, and Cuſtomes, of the Primitive Inhabitants are clearly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monſtrated from that Nation, many old Monuments illuſtrated, and the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce with that People, as well as the <hi>Greeks,</hi> plainly ſet forth: Collected out of approved <hi>Greek</hi> and <hi>Latin</hi> Authors. Together with a Chronological Hiſtory of this Kingdom, from the firſt Traditional beginning untill the year of our Lord 800 when the name of <hi>Britain</hi> was changed into <hi>England.</hi> Faithfully Collected out of the beſt Authors, and diſpoſed in a better Method than hitherto hath been done, with the Antiquities of the <hi>Saxons</hi> as well as <hi>Phoenicians, Greeks,</hi> and <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This Firſt Volume is publiſhed and is ready to be delivered to all thoſe that are pleaſed to ſubſcribe to the two next Volumes intended to be publiſhed.</p>
            <p>The Second Volume is <hi>Anglia,</hi> being a Continuation of the Hiſtory from the year 800. to the end of Queen <hi>Elizabeths</hi> Reign; wherein ſhall be ſhewn the Firſt eſtabliſhment of Monarchy by the <hi>Saxons,</hi> their good Government evid<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d by their own Records, with the Revolutions of State by the <hi>Danes</hi> and <hi>Normans.</hi> Moreover ſhall be added in its proper place, an Account of that part of the Holy War in which <hi>England</hi> was concerned; with many other things of great uſe and benefit, that have hitherto been Omitted in all our Engliſh Chronicles.</p>
            <p>The Third Volume is <hi>Britannia Magna,</hi> beginning at the Reign of King <hi>James</hi> and ending at the time of the moſt happy Reſtauration of his preſent Majeſty King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second.</p>
            <p>THE performance of this work cannot be effected without great Labour and Charge, therefore the Author <hi>Aylett Sammes</hi> of <hi>Chriſts Colledge</hi> in <hi>Cambridg,</hi> ſince of the <hi>Inner-Temple,</hi> doth hereby requeſt the Aſſiſtance of all ſuch Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men as are lovers of Hiſtory, and deſire to have the Miſtakes of our late Chroni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles Rectified to Subſcribe to the ſame; and to receive the Firſt Volume (upon their Subſcribing to the other two) at 14 s. bound, and to pay 16 s. a piece for the other two Volumes unbound, when they ſhall be ready to be delivered.</p>
            <p>Whoſoever procureth ſix ſubſcribers that will Receive the parts as they ſhall be publiſh't and pay the prices above mentioned for them, ſhall have a book of each Volume in quiers preſented him gratis.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>VVee whoſe names are here underwritten doe promiſe to receive the firſt part at 14 s. bound and doe hereby Subſcribe for the other two parts at the prices a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove mentioned if wee approve of them when wee ſee them printed</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>wit. our hands Dated <date>the <gap reason="blank" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈1 span left blank〉</desc>
                     </gap> 1677</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
